<?xml version="1.0"?>
<provider service="org.freedesktop.ContextKit">
 <doc>
Core Context Properties
=======================

This is the list of the core contextual properties of the Maemo
platform.

*NOTE:* Most of these properties are unstable and their definition will
change for some time still.  Only the ones explicitly marked as stable
should be used for now.

 </doc>
 <root>
   <node name="Context">
     <node name="Screen">
       <doc>
Display screens
---------------

These properties talk about the display screens of the device.
       </doc>
       <key name="TopEdge">
	 <choice>
	   <const string="top"/>
	   <const string="bottom"/>
	   <const string="left"/>
	   <const string="right"/>
	 </choice>
         <doc>
The edge of the main display screen where the user expects
the top-most UI elements to be.  Possible values are the
strings "top", "bottom", "left", and "right", which refer to
the edges of the screen in its normal orientation as defined
by the graphics hardware.  _(stable)_
         </doc>
       </key>
       <key name="IsCovered">
	 <bool/>
	 <doc>
Whether or not the main display screen is covered and can
not be seen by the user.  This might mean that the device is
laying face down on a table, or that its lid is closed if it
has one.  _(stable)_
	 </doc>
       </key>
     </node>
     <node name="Location">
       <doc>
Location
--------

Information about the geographic location of the device.
       </doc>
       <key name="Streets">
	 <repeat><string/></repeat>
	 <doc>
The names of the nearby streets, as a list of strings.  The list might
be empty when the current location is not near any street, or there
might be more than one name in the list, when we are at an
intersection.
	 </doc>
       </key>
       <key name="City">
	 <string/>
	 <doc>
The name of the current city in the users language, as a string.
	 </doc>
       </key>
       <key name="State">
	 <string/>
	 <doc>
The name of the current state in the users language, as a string.
	 </doc>
       </key>
       <key name="StateCode">
	 <string/>
	 <doc>
The ISO 3166-2 code of the current state, as a string.  See
link:http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISO_3166-2[here] for more
information.  This value of this property includes the IS3166-1
alpha-2 prefix, as is usual for ISO 3166-2 codes.
	 </doc>
       </key>
       <key name="Country">
	 <string/>
	 <doc>
The name of the current country in the users language, as a string.
	 </doc>
       </key>
       <key name="CountryCode">
	 <string/>
	 <doc>
The ISO 3166-1 alpha-2 code of the current country, as a string.  See
link:http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISO_3166-1[here] for more
information.
	 </doc>
       </key>
       <key name="Continent">
	 <string/>
	 <doc>
The name of the current continent, as a string.
	 </doc>
       </key>
       <key name="Planet">
	 <string/>
	 <doc>
The name of the current planet (or dwarf planet), as a string.
	 </doc>
       </key>
     </node>
     <node name="Connectivity">
       <doc>
Network connectivity
--------------------

Information about the network connectivity of the device.
       </doc>
     </node>
     <node name="Situation">
       <doc>
Situations
----------

Information about the _situation_ the device is in.
       </doc>
       <key name="IsDark">
	 <bool/>
	 <doc>
Whether or not it is dark.
	 </doc>
       </key>
     </node>
   </node>
 </root>
</provider>
